what do you have to learn and how do you
learn it this is a tough question and it
starts by breaking down the different
things you have to learn into
categories in order to win to succeed
and I don't like spending a lot of time
on the nature of learning there there
are I mean I I do geek out about it on
my own but if you're watching this video
because it's a prerequisite to you know
going on and learning more more more of
the stuff that I'm going to talk about
in order to get a job which is obviously
the fundamental goal of this channel um
then you know this this might be it
might seem like extra like you don't
need it I'm going to start with a story
um when my wife was uh working at a
company that shall not be named um she
was regularly responsible to uh
interview people and to assess people
and decide whether they were the best
candidate for the job and they used a
term an acronym called SCA I know you
think this is we're going to use a
pneumonic device here SCA think of like
you know I don't know really bad skrc
mixes or something to help you remember
so skills knowledge and abilities
actually that's not what
SCA you think I would know music after
playing so much music SCA is like Rasta
reg music what isn't it I should
probably restart just no we'll keep
going we'll keep
going what however you want to remember
it ska so skills knowledge and abilities
and what are the differences between
them and I this is actually a question
to the group right now take a moment and
pause and answer and if if we have
people in the audience here who want to
try try to take a stab I would love to
see your comments scroll across the
bottom of the screen right now right now
what is the difference and you can tell
I'm going to tell you right but go ahead
and take a stab at what you think the
difference is spend some time thinking
about it why are skills knowledge and
abilities
separate and you know I this really
shocked me because I thought I mean I
I've spent an unusually large amount of
time trying to figure out what the
domain specific model which is a fancy
way of saying the terminology and
everything you use to talk about a thing
uh what is it for when it comes to
education and
um you know like what's the difference
between a task and a skill and a job and
a career and um you know an ability and
all this stuff so these are kind of the
kind of things that you need to to know
about so the bottom line is is very
simple I'm going to start with abilities
okay abilities are generally the things
that are innate and they while the
category of ability
um so let me give you an example um in a
job posting somebody could say you need
to be able to lift 200
lb right or or 80 pounds or whatever 200
is a lot
actually there's no jobs for that you
have to be like the Hulk himself you
know but that's an ability right you
have to be able you have to be able to
slam dunk right that's in the job
description for several you know uh NBA
positions if you want to that you can't
learn that you can learn how to slam
dunk and be a really short person per
short prove of that back in whatever the
80s um the point is is that abilities
are the innate things uh that are
largely stuff you just have to accept
about yourself and who you are and where
you are and that is the reason I'm
mentioning it first because having
taking stock of your abilities is super
important upfront and I have a very sad
story uh to share about abilities
I almost don't want to say it because
somebody's going to hear this story and
they're going to think oh I can't do
that um but I I I want I want to mention
abilities first because abilities are
the things that you need to assess very
easily and quickly because if you don't
have the ability and it's not one of
these extremely rare abilities that can
be developed such as lifting more weight
you can build up that ability but
there's going to be a maximum to that
ability right right um and that goes for
mental abilities too I am in my 50s and
my ability to recall information
remember things has definitely declined
now there's probably things I could do
to make it better right my ability
however to you know bike for 120
kilometers has gone up because I've
spent a year and a half developing that
ability so so it's really important that
you know what your abilities are upfront
they are the most important things for
you to assess because the abilities take
a long long time to improve a really
long time and I would say something like
typing um is is something that falls
into the abilities uh category okay uh
because you know it is something that
kind of stays with you abilities
sometimes are the kind of things that
can can diminish depending on how if
they're related to physical things they
can diminish over time and then you no
longer are qualified for whatever uh
someone is going to trust you to do
right if you if you can't lift the
minimum amount of weight you cannot do a
certain job period you just can't if you
do not have opposable thumbs there are
certain jobs you can't do that does not
mean that we're you know biased against
you or anything it just means different
job requires so here's the
story um I had an autistic guy and
before I complete this rest of the story
I want you to know that I have two
autistic uh Sons I've had artistic
people in my life my whole life I would
say probably 20 or 30% of the people
that I dealt with um when I for those
eight or nine years that I was at skill
stack about 20 to 30% of them were on
the Spectrum some way in fact autistic
people tend to be attracted to it
careers for lots of reasons um and this
is not about autism it's about this one
story um and this one autistic boy's uh
ability deficiency to do what he dreamed
of doing and this is a very
heartbreaking story I I I may break down
telling the story so so this this guy um
B F came and I and I you know I kept
with him uh for two years um you know
and and he was making very very small
progress um but it was really clear that
he wasn't mentally
in again I hate saying this right it it
wasn't that he didn't have the ability
it was that he was going to have to work
a hundred times harder than everybody
else uh to be able to to do the same
things that other and this this this
kid's dream on top of everything else
was to go into game development like
many people when they're teenagers which
is a horrible idea by the way game
development is one of the worst careers
you could ever pick in the technology
sector for lots of reasons I'll put in
another another video if you're still
that passionate about it fine but just
be ready know what you're getting into I
promise you if you want to make games do
it on the side and enjoy it and make
money at it on the side and have
something else that pays the bills
because if you make it your career
career you'll learn to hate it in my
opinion so anyway this guy on top of him
wanting to his dream was to was to make
games and it became really really
obvious and you know the thing is so
hard about me looking back at this is
because it took two years so it was
about two years of you know and I kept
telling myself I mean you know when I
tell this story I'm always afraid that
that someone outside of it going to say
oh you were happy to take their money
for two years before he told them that
he couldn't do it no I was legitimately
sincerely trying to help him grow and do
what he dreamed of doing and I the thing
that sucks so bad about this story is
his passion it is very very hard to find
people who have the level of passion and
commitment to do what it takes in Tech
period let alone you know to join to
have a tech lifestyle and everything let
alone to try to do it in the game
development world so when you know I I
interviewed people and I I make sure
that they you know before they come in
that things are you know our
expectations are set and met and I
definitely did that with his parents and
he had salted their parents amazing
absolutely amazing parents and it
doesn't pay the bills no and you know so
he help you know pay for your hobby or
whatever so so you know we had an
agreement we had an agreement so anybody
outside watching this I want you to
understand that I was very diligent
about sitting down with the parents of
many of the younger people anyway the
adults also had an interview but we
would sit down and we would agree okay
what are what are the expectations you
have of me what do you what do you want
here and and the story ends with me
having a very very just I can't I don't
even like remembering that day I just
don't it's just so horrible I had to
break his heart I had to tell him I had
to tell him I took him for a walk and
and I I I tried as hard as I could you
know I was like I was like how you doing
he's like well you know I'm I'm excit
I'm trying and he was he was coming in
and he was having his Spirit defeated
every single time he was coming and it
started to I could see it was starting
to like wear on him it was starting to
wear on his soul like because all the
other people in the group and this is
why one other reason I went to
one-on-one I wasn't one-on-one then and
you know he was in the room with the
rest of them and and he didn't have a I
would try I give him a personal ta and
everything and he still was comparing
himself to everybody else in the room
and I could tell it was like wearing on
him you know on his soul and at that
point I was like okay
I cannot have someone leave my learning
community feeling like a Perpetual
failure this just cannot happen I am not
having this so I had to have a very very
difficult talk and I had to I had to sit
down with him and I had to say listen I
said I see the passion that you have or
what you want to do and I know this is
your dream and I said but I just I just
I think I sense that you are getting
this but you are going to be struggling
your entire life with this specific spe
ific thing if you try to do
this and it just deflated him it just
deflated him it took it he was like he
thought I didn't have faith in him
anymore I just it just makes me sick to
think about
it I have a really really really hard
time with this story because I had to
tell him I had to tell him look I am not
the you know and it was just so hard it
was so hard good morning we're making a
video just so you know so I had to tell
this this passion
wonderful amazing human being and I had
autistic kids of my own who I had to
have the same conversations with that
they were going to be struggling 10 to
100 times more I basically had to set an
expectation with
him and I had to say look you know you
you're not going to be able to do this
if you if if you do this you're going to
the other people that are going to be in
game development the companies that are
paying the money they're going to go
with the people that they can hire who
can do the same thing with much less
CLE and and it was just it just was
horrible it was absolutely horrible and
and I told I said but you know what you
doesn't have to be your job you can do
it because you like it and you can move
at your own pace and stuff he goes yeah
I guess I can do that and then I had the
conversation I had the conversation with
his parents as well and um you know his
parents they they you know he was there
because it was at the time it was a sort
of a way for him to to to do something
because he was struggling in every other
thing he was doing out there in school
and everything he was everything was a
struggle and this is one thing he really
loved and they they I told him I said
listen this is this I can see that he's
you know he's starting to
feel you know actually this is one of
the stories that led to me doing
one-on-one mentoring I told you about
that right this is one of the way
reasons I went to one-on-one mentoring
had I been one-on-one mentoring him had
my business model been set up to do
one-on-one mentoring this would not be
an issue this would not be an issue at
all and in fact when I when I went to
one-on-one mentoring I had two or three
people that were similar cases that the
the there was one in particular that was
really extreme and the parents will they
knew very very much that this was going
to be uh you know a one-on-one thing and
it wasn't necessarily going to be for
him to get a career but this other case
was different from that and the lesson I
learned was mixing people with different
learning abilities uh in the same room
unless you have a really unless you have
the ability to really separate them out
if you're building camaraderie between
all the people at the same time that
that those people have to sort of see
how each other is doing whether or not
they're competitive or not they are
going to compare themselves to one
another and the other case of this that
happened it's another short story what
happened to this guy his parents decided
that at that time that it was better for
their their son to to go to find
something else and it was not worth
putting the the pain on them and that
ripped my soul I mean that that just
destroyed me inside because I had become
a close friend of this person for the
last two years and I I had to watch him
leave um and the other story that's
related to this is kind of a negative
story was when I um there were two kids
I've told this story before uh there was
one guy who i' had been mentoring for
two years and and and by the way what
did I do about that right I corrected it
here's another story that led to me
correcting this situation the next story
involves somebody who had been with me
brilliant kid really motivated same sort
of situation no particular learning
disabilities that I was aware of and and
he was doing great for like two or three
years actually and he had a really great
friend who was a competitor in in uh one
of these knowledge bowls he was really
motivated he was extremely passionate
really intelligent and he referred him
he referred him he said i' really love
to do uh I really love for this for my
best friend to join so this guy who had
been with me for two or three years
suddenly had a new person in the group
right and this was back when I thought
so because of that last story I went
from like 16 or eight in a group down to
three maximum and it's very hard to
maintain you know a business with three
people in a class it's just hard and
keep it affordable and so anyway this
group that's why I said fine we'll go
down I I'll go down to three is the
maximum but preferably two right I said
okay well at least it's two people I
used to have a theory of about having
three that was enough for it to not be
competitive but they would still have
fun with each other would still have the
social element of it and because I mean
when moving down to the the numbers down
this is this is about abilities okay so
so anyway this boy invent you know
invited his friend to start coming to
his session and they after after three
months um I want to say it was 3 months
um it became the the the person that I
had been mentoring all this other time
uh quit just straight up quit like that
it just left didn't give me any signs of
it and you know it's it's kind of this
is partially a story about me failing
because I wasn't I didn't see any of the
signs I didn't see them I should have
been more attuned to the signs of it I
should have had more conversations with
him uh but he just pulled out he just
left and you can probably guess why so
his friend that he had invited um to do
all this stuff was
extremely uh he he had he had I have
failed you Anakin yes he had the skills
I mean he had I don't know what you want
to call it but his ability to process
and to learn and to to to was way faster
than his
friend and and he not only did he catch
up to his friend but he passed his
friend like and his friend had been with
me for like two years and it's it's
really sad because rather than talk to
him about well let's look at the reasons
that he's learning faster than you and
what you're going to have to do to keep
up Etc rather than do that he just he
just left he just left he just stopped
coming never had a chance to have an
opportunity to talk to them about it and
and his friend stated it he took over
his spot and he was like really active
and everything you know what the
difference was time the the guy that was
new the guy that was new spent probably
6 hours outside of class outside of the
session practicing on things when we
when I would give him something to do
I'd say go home and practice this and
you know do these things the other guy
the only thing he did was his 60 minutes
or so every week that was it he didn't
have any outside drive to do
anything and then we and you guys
already know the graph it goes like this
right that's how the graph goes when it
comes to learning and abilities you know
it goes like this right but but this kid
who had been doing 6 hours a week
because he felt like he was behind his
learning went like this maybe a little
bit but it was a constant path up
meanwhile the other guys was like this
he kept learning and forgetting learning
and forgetting and the other one went
whoop and he just caught straight up
with him in three months he had all the
same skills that his friend had had and
and whether it was a learning disability
no I don't think it was it was a
difference of
commitment um to the learning but I do I
dare say that there was also so some
some some difference of ability uh
related to that and maybe the reason
that the other person didn't want to do
um you know that stuff every is because
their ability to learn it uh was harder
something about it was you know innate
lead more difficult for them so so as so
again the point of this video
hi the point of this video of this part
of the video is the most important thing
that you can assess about yourself
before you jump down the path of a Tech
Career or any career is what are your
abilities you need to be very honest
with yourself and you need to get people
around you that are going to help you
assess what your raw abilities are and
some of them are going to say thing that
you disagree with that's fine take it
all and stride you're ultimately the
authority on this particular thing but
you need to assess your abilities be
above everything else and once you get
those once you know that you have the
abil and this is this is by the way one
of those places where
um other people will sometimes lie to
you I'll tell the very quick version of
the story with the mom who came to me I
had a housewife Mom I'm using terms that
she used um who wanted to learn how to
code and she had the ability to do it
but she had no time but the people in
her world were telling her she couldn't
do it she absolutely could do it she had
the mo motivation and passion but she
also had a bunch of responsibilities
that the people in her world decided
were more important and pressured her on
and made fun of her for her and so she
dropped out I'm telling you a bunch of
fail stories here um hopefully that you
know there's been hundreds of not
thousands of people who have
successfully moved forward but these are
all situations that people if they had
spent more time assessing their
abilities uh in addition to their
motivation and their the time
constraints and stuff like that um in
her case I don't think it was a learning
ability at all it or even a motivation
ability her the lack of ability on her
part was she didn't have ability to
dedicate the time to it so it's more of
a time thing not really an ability but
still qualifies it's in that space of
like I have no AB no no ability to
change it it's something that it's going
to take a very long time for me to
change um yeah and then sometimes you
think you're interested in one thing and
you go down the other one um abilities
can be stronger different this is
another thing too the reason I'm I'm
harping on abilities before we do SC
skills and knowledge which we will talk
about briefly today too as well they're
easier to talk about by the way much
easier so the the other thing about
ability that I want to talk about is
that when when you um once you have
outlined the abilities um and you've
identify what your abilities are that
you're strong at you will enjoy it more
you will enjoy it people naturally
gravitate to the things where they have
natural ability they enjoy it that's
what they want to do so a lot of times
your passion is also the thing that you
have a lot of inate ability to do my
wife for example is ridiculously good
artist oh my God she what when I watch
her just like she in like 60 seconds she
can like rough in a figure drawing that
would take me two weeks to even begin to
understand how she did it and I I just
don't have the ability could I develop
it maybe maybe I could it's not really a
skill in that case it's just to her to
her it's an ability because she can see
things that I just can't see my brain
just doesn't work that way now I can do
things that she can't do at all she's
completely toned
up I love her so much but she she this
is her words she's 100% toned up and I
bought her a ukulele and she tried to
play it and it's kind of a funny story
because her her her mom kept screaming
at her are you torturing that ukulele
again she you know she she can't she has
she has she she doesn't care though she
will sing baby she will sing at the top
of her lungs and you know you know how
much I value music and stuff and I I
just think it's cute I think it's
amazing I don't think she's as toned dep
as she thinks she is but she does she
definitely doesn't have the musical
ability that I have and I'm not that's
not a comparison that's just to make the
point that we all have innate abilities
that we gravitate to because we like it
it feels good we're good at it um
inevitably We compare ourselves to
others and in those when we have a
natural ability it feels good to be
better than somebody else I hate to say
it but it does right it feels good to be
naturally better at somebody else and
and to say look what my god-given
abilities are you know some people would
call it talents whatever um and and I do
think you should discover what they are
you should well them so that's a lot of
talk and a lot of stories about
abilities hopefully that'll help you uh
beyond anything else that'll help you
become very very honest with yourself
and what your abilities are before you
go charging down a path that could lead
to extreme
disappointment uh another story for me
really quickly I wanted to be a
basketball star when I was I used to sit
on my driveway and I would shoot hoops
every day for 3 hours and it just wasn't
happening I was too short I didn't have
the base coordination I could do certain
things but I I was never going to be a
pro same thing with like uh
Triathlon you know there was a lot of
doping in that Prof that thing as well
so I I did you know there knowing what
your abilities are and and musically you
right I play guitar at the fir slide I
would never do so you know
professionally I don't have that kind of
ability um anyway so let's go on to
skills and knowledge really quickly
before we leave today um skill a skill
is the ability to perform a specific
task okay and um I'm going to say that
I'm going to keep this video long anyway
um a skill is the ability not the
ability a skill is being able to do a
specific task right um that that doesn't
have any innate ability a skill is a
something that can be learned so um
typing some people would use it as call
it a skill yes you can learn Tope type
but the speed at which you type is based
on ability so there is a little bit of
overlap for sure um but you know typing
is a skill that can be learned obviously
um but you know at a certain point
you're going to be limited by whatever
your Baseline abilities that's the point
so the the skill stack and the beginner
boost and all that stuff that we're
doing is focused on um helping you
identify what your abilities are so you
can build them up if you need to and can
do them um and s sort of decide if you
Tech is for you and in the middle it's
and most most of the content is in the
middle it's skill related it's i setting
up a kubernetes cluster it's it's it's
operating from the terminal it's doing a
command line query from the terminal
it's using VI uh effectively to edit a
file on a remote system it's using SSH
to go into a system these are all tasks
these are very specific tasks and a lot
of times this the tasks are can be
broken down into subtasks and um I I do
another video about this about about how
this relates to like The Scouting system
forer Badges and things it breaks down
specific tasks into their subtasks and
how you would do that it's also the
basis of all the recipe books like
O'Reilly has and everything how do I
change the permissions on this file how
do I send an email from the command line
how do I you know make a web page how do
I populate a form how do I store the
data in a database these are all skills
most of the content 100 you know I would
say 90% of the content on this channel
Channel and in skill stack begin boost
and that's why skill is in the name is
on building the skills that go into your
stack depending on where you want to go
what job you want and of course in the
Boost the foundational stack that
everybody should have everyone should
know how to install a Linux system
everyone should know how to remotely
connect to a system everyone should know
how to make a basic web document and put
it on GitHub these are foundational
skills that build upon one another and
can be composed together in fact in many
ways um a skill is like and when we get
into coding you'll understand I love
this I I have some videos I started on
programming humans because that's what
they are a skill is like a procedure in
fact the term is called a procedure in
the business world or in the military
world right like like special ops why is
it called
op because it's a special operation what
is an operation an operation is the
execution of a number of things to
achieve a specific result you know in a
very organized way it's Bas to do a
special op you're pretty much
programming to strategize a special op
you literally are programming that op
into the team and that team has to be
capable of executing that op that means
they there's a bunch of skills and tasks
and and and abilities that they need to
be able to deploy in order to do that
but but you can break down uh the
development of a human being the
programming of a human or even a team
into a bunch of procedures and
operations that you know involve skills
and you can basically write code for
people in order to do things in fact
that's that's a lot of what systems
management is Business Systems
management and business analysts do is
they break down the systems and I'm not
talking about tech I'm talking about
what are the business systems that have
to be done in order to produce a result
and then and then they do all the whole
thing and that entire it's if I'm
geeking out on this particular point is
because I really love it the the idea
the idea of being able to
program uh yeah to be able to program
you know a human or an
organization uh by writing it when you
write documentation and stuff you're
largely doing this in fact I spent a lot
of time on this I'll just mention it I
might work on it again later creating
something called the open credential
Merit system uh ocms aams as in aams
Razer and what it was designed to be is
a way to document uh what you need to
learn what are the skills in order to
execute to do a thing and then you could
basically you know base your job
descriptions as well as matching your
skill set your skill stack with the job
description uh by having a common way to
document all of that in a in a line item
you know starts with a verb kind of way
you know know you know know the
difference between blah um you know
discover what your career opportunities
are you all of these like on liners
which are pretty much the same as
procedures or functions in coding if you
know what that I'm talking about so stay
tuned for that I I actually really would
like to get with other um pedagogues out
there and and come up with the rest of
the the ocms uh system I've registered
all the domains and everything because I
think it would be really fun to itemize
um all the learning that has to happen
all the skills in particular that need
to be learned to go with a particular uh
role and whether that role be you know
webdb or whatever and then you would
have a role and and a credential that's
associated with that this is this is
what people do in education all the time
they just call it different things um
and Mar pades is the same thing anyway
so skills can be broken down they can be
itemized you can learn to do the
different thing and they can be
practiced they can be done you practice
doing skills by when you do lead code
you practice doing skills when you do
your own projects when you do mini
projects or macro projects anytime
you're doing that practice you're
practicing your skills so they they are
very easy to do um and they they tend
skills tend to to to do better when you
memorize them more and so if you're
going to spend time committing abilities
of course you know they're innate and so
lifting weight and stuff like that you
have to just either there it's not right
you have to maintain it skills can also
benefit by how fast you can type or how
you know being able to remember how to
make an HTML page I made a video about
how free Camp failed because it didn't
reinforce the skill skill of making a
page right it never stuck never stuck in
their head why right so and they
couldn't really do it and then other
people that I tested they were able to
do it from scratch from their head why
one of them stuck and one didn't so how
much of this you memorize that you know
skills benefit from memorization but
they can also benefit from chat GPT or
looking it up really quickly and justed
time learning which I'll do a separate
video on so that that so skills skills
is the fundamental Focus um I still
think abilities is going to be the
GateKeeper and the blocker for most
people so make sure you assess that but
skills is the the the the way you know
being able to speak a foreign language
Etc that's where we're going to spend
the time and then there's knowledge now
knowledge knowledge is the know thing
like if you if you're having a hard time
categorizing something in your notes
about what you should learn and like
like I have right here like look right
here there's a bunch of knowledge stuff
here no no no when the verb is
no then then you know that you're
dealing with knowledge uh historical
context um you know the things that you
need that give you context these are not
skills these are I need to know um I
mean adding one plus one together is a
skill knowing why you need to know
mathematics is knowledge right and some
people would use knowledge as with a
much broader umbrella they would use it
to group all the skills under it um I
like that it's broken out out uh in the
way that as I mentioned my wife's um uh
company uh you know provided for and
when by the way when they were doing an
assessment uh they would break down the
categories ability skills and knowledge
and when they did their yearly
assessment they' say okay what are the
abilities you need that you have that
you've executed on or that you need to
slowly work on improving what are your
skills that you need or or are you
failed at using this year and what is
the knowledge that you need that will
help you to stay motivated and and have
context for everything else for the
skills and abilities that you're using
every day right if you don't have the
knowledge if you don't know about Aaron
Schwarz right how is knowing about Aaron
Schwarz affecting your ability to get a
job right it isn't it it really isn't
but it's maybe going to motivate you and
help you understand why certain skills
are important right so so knowledge the
Baseline knowledge and history and and
and you know do you need to know about
Particle Fever and all the stuff that
happened at CERN to appreciate the to
use the HTML and make web pages you
don't need that no but having the the
knowledge and the context about how the
worldwide web came to be and why that
solution to a problem that existed and
knowing what the problem was
understanding the problem is
knowledge and therefore knowledge is
really key to a Tech Career if you do
not know
what solution you're making if you don't
if you're making a solution and you
don't know what the problem is because
you can't articulate the problem because
you don't have the knowledge about what
this why this is an issue then you have
a knowledge deficit not a skills deficit
and that is a totally different thing so
having knowledge and knowing how to be
aware of the company so I'm about let me
give you one story about this before I
leave this has been quite a long video
but I'm about to move into my role
full-time uh having been a contractor
I've been a full-time employee my whole
life other than the time I ran my own
businesses but but but I now have a
different opportunity they call them
that's what that by the way that's a
that's a HR word opportunity and HR word
the word opportunity is this is
something that you're not doing very
well right now you probably should do
better on it's the politically correct
word for you're failing at this right
now go spend some time with it and which
is not as palatable as opportunity right
so so my opportunity one of my
opportunities is to get a better
understanding of our team's role in the
larger context of a huge multinational
corporation I am delivering on skills
all the time I'm I made you know helped
to create the the central API for
submission of all the machine learning
jobs for you know thousands of um you
know machine learning models and all
that that are directly fundamentally
related to making money for this company
I mean it's it's a big deal but can I
tell you what those applications are do
I understand where those applications
are being deployed how they're being
deployed what happens if if the pieces
that I built stop working what is the
impact to the overall Organization no I
can't I can't tell you that right now I
have a deficit I have a knowledge
deficit I have an opportunity to further
understand my role and the role of my
team in the larger and the Lar ler
Enterprise and that is knowledge that is
knowledge so that concludes this
video knowing um is aptitude a synonym
for
skill no I I think aptitude is a synonym
for um
ability a an aptitude for something
means that you are more likely to become
proficient in a thing because it's EAS
easier for you and the fact that it's
easier for you is related to your innate
abilities or to your hard to change
abilities and and whether it be you know
you need to do more brain training so
your brain works more efficiently these
are not things that can be fixed in a
month of boot camp ever right abilities
take years to develop or to decline so
aptitude I think aptitude falls under
the abilities uh if you say well this
person they have a natural aptitude for
languages somebody might say that about
me I do I have a natural aptitude for
not computer languages but I mean it's
kind of a fun side topic right there is
like does somebody who has a natural
aptitude for natural languages also pick
up programming languages
easier I don't know they're all syntax
right and I mean so that would be he has
a natural aptitude for foreign language
he has an aptitude for art they have an
aptitude for sports they have an
aptitude I I think aptitudes are
sort of a collective grouping of
abilities that that that are sort of
focused on a specific type of thing uh
whatever the aptitude is like you know
um for example let me give you another
really fun example anybody know dendi I
I love this example I'll end with this
one okay um LM usage has exploded people
are focusing on full-time Focus Laur I
don't know about that we're not talking
about that right now but um so yeah um
last piece of this so so dendi dendi is
one of my favorite um if you know if you
go go Google dendy Fountain hook uh from
Dota 2 it's probably one of the most I
would say it's got to be one of the top
five moments in all of Esports history
um it's absolutely amazing if you're
into Esports and gaming of any kind I
don't do DOTA lately because this is
like drug I would be addicted to it
completely um but dendi who had a
natural aptitude for gaming is also
a world class classical
pianist yeah so you would say about
dendi is you know he's got the best mid
lanane and the best Pudge in I mean he's
just amazing right but but he has a
natural aptitude and that aptitude that
aptitude for gaming uh also applies to
his aptitude for specifically piano
playing and so he's got he's got the
ability he has he has fingers that are
particularly dextrous and longer um he's
he's you know he's able to process a lot
of things at the same time so his
aptitude for gaming by saying he has an
aptitude for it it's kind of collection
of abilities some physical and some
perhaps mental all of which almost all
of which are innate but some of which
can be de can be developed such as
dexterity dexterity can be developed
finger length can't short of surgery so
you see what I'm saying that's what I
when I I like the the the opportunity to
use that example because because Denny
his aptitude
um his you know for gaming is depending
on his many of his abilities that have
combined to make him really really
powerful for that kind of thing um and
and I think that that goes for uh you
know his ability to do classical music
as well um so anyway I I feel like
people are talking about other things
now that's cool um I think I think we
really kind of covered this so skills
knowledge and abilities or abilities uh
skills and knowledge how however you
want to put it um I kind of like the
abilities skills and knowledge I just
realized that that spells the word
ask ask yourself oh my God that's the
new title for this video ask yourself
what do I have what can I do what do I
need to do wow that needs to be a
t-shirt I see some merch coming bye